Nathanael Jenkins

\(+44 (0)7 960 264 171

Executive Summary

An Aeronautical Engineering student at Imperial College London and scholar of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers with grades equivalent to first class honours. Pursuing a career in the engineering industry, with a desire to gain relevant experience through a summer internship.

Education

MEng Aeronautical Engineering (current)

2020 - 2024

Imperial College London

- Successfully completed first year studies, achieving results equivalent to first class honours (81.43%)
- Awarded a position on the 1st year 'Dean's List' after attaining a grade in the top 10% of the cohort

A-Levels (A*, A*, A*, A*)

2018 - 2020

Peter Symonds College, Winchester

- Produced a grade A* extended project qualification (EPQ) investigating the feasibility of ion propulsion of spacecraft and aircraft
- Networked with globally recognised experts at RAeS, QinetiQ and Purdue University whilst conducting Extended Project research
- Established time-management skills by maintaining a high standard of work whilst studying 4 A-Levels and an Extended Project

10 GCSEs, grades 7-9/A*

2012 - 2018

Robert Mays School, Odiham

■ Achieved grade 9 in seven subjects including Mathematics and Physics, and grade A* in Engineering

Experience

Undergraduate Research Opportunity | 'GPU Parallelisation of a 2D Navier-Stokes Solver' 06/2021 - 08/2021 Imperial College London, Department of Aeronautics, Dr Sylvain Laizet (Supervisor)

- Successfully delivered a C++ solver using SYCL to enable accelerated computation on heterogeneous systems
- Developed an extensive understanding of high-performance heterogeneous computing, particularly GPU offloading
- Utilised industry-leading tools in the Intel oneAPI HPC Toolkit, including use of the VTune profiler for deeper offloading analysis

Aerodynamics and Simulations Engineer

10/2020 -

Imperial College London Rocketry, Altitude Record Team

- Led the aerodynamics and simulations sub-team, using advanced computational methods to develop and test proposed rocket designs
- Improved design strategies to limit the negative impact of financial and regulatory limitations, contributing to the successful design and manufacture of three rockets with a budget of only £500

- Extended use of CFD beyond the scope of undergraduate studies, using StarCCM+ and SU2 on complex computational domains
- Introduced fresh ideas and new perspectives to the team, leading the way towards a new dynamic modelling tool and improved simulation workflows

Duty Manager 03/2020 - 01/2021

The Food Warehouse, Basingstoke

- Promoted from general assistant to duty manager within 5 months, having played an integral role in the opening of this new wholesale-type store
- Confidently managed busy store periods, with total responsibility for store operations, safety and security

General Assistant 10/2018 - 02/2020

The Mill House, Odiham

Work Experience Placements

07/2017, 08/2018

NATS Southampton, AECOM Basingstoke, Miller Hare London

■ Enhanced commercial awareness through experience in three engineering companies, each with unique goals and challenges

Achievements and Memberships

Member, British Human Powered Flying Club

2021 -

Student Affiliate, Institute of Mechanical Engineers

2020 -

IMechE James Clayton Undergraduate Scholar

2020 - 2024

Student Affiliate, Royal Aeronautical Engineering Society

2018 -

Arkwright Engineering Scholar

2018 - 2020

 Recognised as a future leader in engineering by the Southampton University Faculty of Engineering and Physical Sciences

F1inSchools Alumnus, Judge, and Event Volunteer

2017 -

- Achieved 5th place at the 2017 World Finals in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, out of 51 global teams
- Inspire the next generation of engineers by mentoring current teams in engineering and professional skills
- Committed to judging at Regional and National Finals, since 2019
- Volunteered at 2020(21) World Finals, preparing teams from across the globe for live-streamed interviews

Software and Tools



Fusion360



SolidWorks



MATLAB



Khronos SYCL







oneaPi